hayhouseuniversity.com 2017-06-25

# Privacy Policy

Hay House has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. Protecting the privacy and security of your personal information is a priority at Hay House, and we believe that a single, comprehensive privacy policy that is straightforward and clear is in the best interests of our customers and our businesses.

This Privacy Policy applies to personal and other information that may be collected when you interact with Hay House, Inc., which consists of websites owned, operated and managed by Hay House, including each website that links to this Privacy Policy. 

When you interact with our site, we collect two types of information Personally Identifiable Information (PII) and Non-Personally Identifiable Information (NPII).

**Personally Identifiable Information (“PII”) is data about you that is personally identifiable.**

Our online e-newsletter asks users to give us contact information (like their name and e-mail address). This information is used to contact the visitor when necessary about special promotions, and discounts, and is never divulged to third parties in a manner that personally identifies you. Our site uses an order form for customers to request information, products, and services. We collect visitor's contact information (like their e-mail address) and financial information (like their account or credit card numbers). Contact information from the order form is used to send orders, information about our company, and occasional future promotional material. The customer's contact information is also used to get in touch with the customer when necessary regarding the order. Financial information that is collected is used to bill the user for products and services. We do not store credit card details nor do we share customer details with any 3rd parties in a manner that personally identifies the customer.  
If authorized by you, we may also access profile and other information from services like Facebook.

**Sharing with third parties  
** All personally identifiable data provided by individuals is maintained in confidence by Hay House. There are instances, however, in which personally identifiable and non-personally identifiable information is shared with third parties, as described below. 

With respect to personally identifiable information provided to Hay House, Hay House may, from time to time, provide information to certain third-party vendors for efficiency purposes in providing administrative services such as billing, delivery and pay-outs, or for other related services. Vendors and service providers are contractually required to keep confidential the information received, and may not use it for any purpose other than to carry out the services they perform on our behalf. 

**Choice/Opt-Out**  
Please contact [Customer Service](http://www.hayhouse.com/contact/email/) to request the removal of your PII from our database or to no longer receive future communications.

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information** Non-Personally Identifiable Information (“NPII”) data is collected by Hay House and ad technology partners and is used for retargeting. We, and/or one or more of our ad technology partners, may collect NPII from people who visit our website(s). This data is anonymous, and can include information such as web pages you’ve viewed, date and time of pageviews, domain type, location information associated with your IP address, and your interactions to an ad delivered by us or our ad technology partners. Our ad technology partners use different methods to collect this type of data, including cookies and web beacons (pixel tags or clear gifs). 

Cookies are small text files that can store information. There are two types of cookies: session cookies and persistent cookies. Session cookies expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies stay on your computer until you delete them. Hay House may use both session and persistent cookies to customize your web experience and to analyze web traffic. Hay House uses cookies and web beacons in the delivery of display advertisements to our website visitors and to our partner website visitors on various sites across the internet. 

**Third party web analytics services**    
We work with third party service providers, including but not limited to Google Analytics, to help us better understand how you use the Hay House Websites. These third party service providers will place cookies on your computer to collect information such as how you were referred to the Hay House Website, how you navigate around the Hay House Website, what you purchase and what traffic is driven by various marketing methods. This information will help us to better serve you and provide you with more personalized information and product offerings. We do not allow third party service providers to collect your credit card information, e-mail address or password information. These third party service providers may only use your personal information to perform services for us and may not share your personal information with anyone else, or use it for any other purpose, except on an aggregated, non-personally identifiable basis.  
  
To learn more about the privacy practices of Google, you may review its privacy policy located [here](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). To disable the Google Analytics cookie and other third party web analytics service provider cookies, you can choose to have your browser notify you when cookies are being written to your computer or accessed, or you can disable cookies.

**Social networking sites**    
When you use a Hay House app on a social networking site or choose to join (or "like") a Hay House page on a social networking site, the social networking site may provide us with certain information about you, including but not limited to your "likes". Please see the privacy policy for the applicable social networking site to learn more about how these sites share your personal information.

**Third party sites  
** This site contains links to other sites. Hay House is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.

Hay House is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to amazon.com.

**Data retention policy**    
We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you with services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Accessing your information**    
You have the right to ask us not to use your personal information for direct marketing purposes. You also have the right to request a copy of the personal information that we hold about you and to have any inaccuracies rectified. Please note that, as permitted by law, we may charge a nominal fee for information requests and may require you to prove your identity. Following a request, we will use reasonable efforts to supply, correct or delete personal information about you in our files.

**Contacting the Web site**  
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact Hay House at the address below.

Hay House, Inc.  
P.O. Box 5100  
Carlsbad, CA 92018-5100  
(800) 654-5126
